hi everyone this is David Cassidy and
it's a joy to welcome you to the first
of what we hope will be many gospel
conversations with the alliance for
Mission and renewal and with me today is
David RoR who leads a church in East
Nashville and David strain who leads
First Presbyterian Church in Jackson
Mississippi guys I'm going to ask you to
take a minute to introduce yourselves uh
let me start with David strain and then
we'll go to David RoR and just talk a
little bit about your ministry what's
going on and then we'll take things from
there yeah thank you David I'm really
glad to be with you both um yeah as you
say I'm the pastor at First Presbyterian
Church in in Jackson Mississippi I'm
from Scotland originally as you can
probably tell um 10 years here at First
Press now just just finished our a
sabatical and much needed very grateful
for it but very glad to be back in
ministry here this is my favorite place
in the world to preach the gospel I love
this congregation and these dear people
and uh yeah so that's a little bit about
me yeah
teric H my name is David RoR has already
been said I'm the the pastor of uh City
Church of East Nashville and I've been
here for two years before that I was a
church planner in Boston massachus for
10 years and um before that I was uh
doing a lot of things work for LA was in
Scotland for a little while I actually
think that David you and I met the first
time at general assembly at the Free
Church so when you were a pastor in
London uh I I I thought about I was
talking to a friend of mine uh the other
day and he mentioned that he thought it
was there so I don't I didn't remember
that at the time but I think that may be
true so that's it's great so but anyway
um East Nashville Tennessee uh my wife
Kelly have two kids Sam and Lucy so uh
enjoying the time here I really really
love Tennessee not particularly this
much this time of year but hopefully
it's going to get really nice very soon
so
uh David Cassidy I'm the pastor at
Spanish River Church in boa Ron Florida
and uh like the other two Davids um had
the great privilege of calling the
United Kingdom home lived there for 10
years but it was ages ago so that was
1979 forward into the late 80s before
coming back to the US so and that wasn't
of course in the you know the glories of
Scotland either that was that was Oxford
and London which were very
nice but I'll take South Florida and my
palm trees I think that's just fine and
delighted to be part of the
conversation um what got this all going
of course is the Overture which is now
before presbyteries in the Presbyterian
Church in America Overture 23 and that
was penned originally by David Str by
the way it's going to get really wild
with three Davids on this right I don't
know if it's a pub or a law firm I'm not
sure the three Davids but it could be
DAV David and David yeah it could be
very fun so uh David why don't we just
start there talk a little bit about um
the the the the thought process the
impulse behind crafting that Overture to
begin with for its arrival at General
Assembly uh earlier this year
yeah
thanks o overtures are they're messy
things right and they they rarely
land first time in the form in which the
denomination Embraces them and sometimes
they take years of denominational
reflection and debate and discussion to
find language that that actually works
yeah we have been talking about the
content of this overture in some form or
another for actually quite a number of
years there are there's now at least one
Overture that has made it into our book
that has come out of that discussion
already um and this was an attempt to
address concerns from different sides of
the church from friends from different
perspectives that I was talking with on
the one hand some were saying we still
feel the need to press for real clarity
about how ministers and elders and
deacons should think and speak of
themselves and their sexuality in light
of biblical
standards and we think that it would be
helpful for us as a denomination to
articulate those things in so many words
so that's one set of concerns there was
another set of concerns saying we hear
that
drive toward
Clarity but we keep hearing vocabulary
being used in there that is il defined
or undefined that may cause more trouble
than it's worth as we press for clarity
let's actually make sure that it brings
Clarity and doesn't create more
confusion um and so trying to listen to
the feedback from previous attempts at
this I've been involved as have both of
you in overtures committees and in disc
discussions around the deliberative
process at general assembly and before
and after general assembly in in
attempting to
find a a path forward that everyone can
can buy into that will bring both
Clarity and
unity um and uh this was an attempt to
to to take a stab at that and
and um by God's grace so far so good uh
encouraged by the kind of consensus that
I'm seeing around this and it's my hope
I really was hoping to save the PCA from
endless rounds of the same discussion in
the same terms which only generates
frustration and means that sometimes we
end up taking our eye off the bigger
goal which is bringing the gospel to the
ends of the
Earth
David what um David RoR I'm gonna have
to clarify so David David RoR uh when
you think
about all the implications
of conversations we're having with with
people about whether not this
is necessary in the light of
past overtures one as David strain
mentioned is already on the books when
we're thinking about that having
conversations with guys what what sort
of push back are we getting
there about what something's needed
right now I think it's a legitimate
question to say like what are the
concerns that are rising up from
different wings of the church and
different individuals within the church
and and I think we need to take those uh
concerns seriously and we need we need
to learn how to listen to one another
better and and try to actually hear uh
what the the kind of the nub of the
concern is I think uh as the three of us
have talked in the past and and others
and I've talked to other people I think
getting to the nub of it is is a
difficult thing sometimes and um I think
on one side uh there there are a number
of things and factors that I think that
play into that I mean we all know that
we are living through uh a very
interesting time culturally where uh
we're all feeling the pressure of uh of
a shifting cultural norms uh Shi
shifting kind of uh perspectives on uh
human sexuality uh shifting uh uh
degrees of of intensity in uh the
critiques that are coming from the
outside about what this issue is about
and uh I think that it is a legitimate
thing to say are we being clear are our
you know internal documents um and
standards clear about what we actually
believe that the scriptures say uh that
is incredibly important and has been
important for centuries um it's why we
write Creeds it's why we write uh
confessions of faith and so these are
incredibly important things to do um it
is another concern on the other side to
ask the question uh are are our
standards sufficiently clear and are we
uh engaging in debate around things
because of fear or because we're uh uh
concerned about what's going on outside
us and we're just not communicating that
well I think in some ways that's been it
seems like the two sides of the debate
that had been going on and I think uh
the process um has been difficult at
times but I think I agree with David
that you know I think that we are moving
toward uh more clarity but also more
Unity on this I I do one of my questions
and I think the questions that I I get a
lot and i' I'd Love Actually to hear
from you guys about this is you know we
we have been through several rounds and
uh you know we had two overtures that
passed through and ended up uh being
passed last year and uh and the you know
a lot of the conversation around that
was that that was going to be you know
the clarity that we needed um and and
then this year we got 23 and uh and and
I think that there are more concerns and
more questions that are coming up and so
I think some of the questions that I'm
I'm getting or the concerns that I'm
getting is you know when is this going
to end as David said is this going to be
an endless kind of you know uh kind of
writing of overtures that we're kind of
going through or uh where are we missing
each other and where are we missing each
other about where the clarity actually
lies that we need because you know I
think you know people I've hear a lot of
actually Unity being built around over
23 right now this year that passes
through but there is concern that like
is this going to be it not obviously not
in the conversation or the end of our
you know need to engage a an
increasingly hostile culture around
these issues but when uh how how much
more do we need to clarify the things
that we have in our in our documents and
where are we missing each other in the
conversation and that's an interesting
question to me like where are we missing
that conversation I'd love to hear from
both of you and and you know what how
did we get here how how do you think
that we're actually we've been missing
each other in this conversation yeah I I
loved where David ended David strain
ended with the note about getting back
to the business of gospel Proclamation
uh getting that to the ends of the Earth
and because that is the work of the
church and we want to be about that it
it seems to me that there's this dual
impulse and I want to honor both
impulses I think they're both very
biblical impulses one to proclaim the
gospel and the other to guard it to
preserve it so Proclamation preservation
so Paul writing to Timothy saying uh
guard the gospel uh in in um 2 Timothy 1
and two the things that you've heard
from me uh in the presence of many
witnesses and Trust to Faithful Men will
be able to teach others also and so on
but also gospel Proclamation so that you
know it's preach the word be faithful in
season and out and so on both of those
are there and I think probably where we
at least in many cases I don't want to
say absolutely but in many cases there's
probably a stronger concern about one of
those two particular emphases um perhaps
more more more strident concerned about
uh the
Purity um and and the preservation of
the gospel and the other the
proclamation of the Gospel the going out
into the world with Mission making sure
we're engaging with the world and not
all of the debates which have taken
place have aided Us in my view in
helping on either front but in
particular shepherding
people and caring for them members of
the church and it's one of the reasons
some of the intensity some of the
combativeness over the last few years
has led to Great dismay and
discouragement in many quarters and so
so One Pastor I talked to recently they
I don't think we can stay in the PCA not
over any doctrinal differences but
because the culture of it is so
combative so I do think it's important
that if we're going to address these
issues and we do think we have Unity on
this and of course there's a particular
focus of this Overture which has to do
with officers it's not about um some
general thing there may be implications
Beyond uh beyond that because we
obviously want officers to be examples
but this particular focus with
requirements of our officers in the
church that um having spoken to that
with Clarity we can we can move forward
I I I just think both of those impulses
are critical to honor and I think we
probably in many
cases have a sense that one of those two
lies more strongly in Hearts than others
depending on maybe some of our our
calling I don't know David strain you
have any thoughts on that I largely
agree I I I think that it depends
sometimes on the
issue um and it's it sometimes surprises
me to see uh who lands where that's not
always as predictable as at first may
appear yeah and um so depending on the
issue so I've observed over the years in
my time in the PCA that when the
denomination when the general assembly
perceives something to be a gospel issue
when it perceives an issue to strike at
the nature of the Gospel or directly
flows as an implication of what it means
to follow Jesus the denomination je
generally lands in the right place every
nearly every yes no doubt in our study
committees and in our deliberative
decision making sometimes it takes a few
swings to get there and and as you say
it can get messy sometimes even a little
ugly along the way uh and and in a
denomination our
size uh you're you're always going to
have
um a variety of
temperaments uh you know some of which
are um more
combative uh than others
and that can give us a bit of a false
read on the mood of the
denomination you know that I'm not
always convinced that the generalist
assembly the tone of a particular debate
is reflective of the mood of the
PCA as a whole um and so I those I offer
that as cautions I think it's sometimes
really easy for us as teaching Elders in
particular we're very concerned and very
engaged in the courts of the church
especially in things like the overtures
committee and the deliberative processes
it's really easy for us to sort of read
the PCA through that through that lens
and that can get really discouraging
and it it can lead us into a really
combative uh stance a sort of them and
US
stance and I I agree that
mission and message are equally
ultimate things um what's the use of
having Clarity on the message if you
don't share it with anyone right what's
the use of being all about reaching the
world if you've lost the message that
will save the world that's right right
so these are equally ultimate must be
held together yeah um but I I don't
think it's right to to to sort of
polarize the denomination say these are
the message guys and those are the
mission guys yeah I think sometimes that
has to do more with the particular Point
under discussion than it does with two
camps my my own
view is that uh our theological
standards the Westminster standards
Express the central stream of what it
means to be a presbyterian
Christian they're not they're not on the
right or the left the westmin
standards is in my judgment biblical
Christianity most fully
expressed and to really grasp that ought
to lead us
to deep convictions wedded to an irenic
spirit
uh a a desire to stand together with all
those who share like Precious Faith with
us without wavering on our commitments
and I do think that part of the
broader
uh landscape of discussion in our
culture right now
has uh bled into the church so that so
that there can be a real
polarization um a lack of listening a
great deal of heat not always a great
deal of light now I do think that there
are in a number of places substantive
differences of opinion both about the
message and about the mission no
question terms of methodology and yeah
yeah yeah no question what what needs to
be
emphasized um and how best to get the
word out yeah and and those are real
differences but often we're talking past
each other fighting about what we assume
each other is
saying rather than having genuine
discussion about those real differences
we have so much that we
share um but you wouldn't always know it
especially if you tune into the debates
at General Assembly um and that's
actually that's actually a factor is
tuning into the debates I mean now with
internet access and live streaming
everything and uh the way social media
works everybody's in on some of how the
sausage is made right and and uh that
hasn't that that overflows into the way
in which discussions take place on a on
a wider basis there's also and and David
RoR was talking about this a little bit
what what's fueled some of this I think
sometimes there are expectations that
these things can be easily resolved
quickly
resolved um historically the church has
never been in a huge
hurry not just the PCA on major major
doctrinal and Theological issues going
all the way back it it it takes on many
it's taken on many occasions decades
even centuries to reach Unity on point
so we do have a kind of age in which we
expect instantaneous results and then
there's pressure within the media
especially on leaders to um go down a
certain path take a certain stand etc
etc and um that's that that can't
actually be helpful to the way in which
we can work together
right one of the most helpful things my
dad ever said to me I remember sitting
on the floor of general assembly with
him when I was in high school I think
and he said and I remember you know
somebody getting really angry at the
microphone and asking what that was
about and he and he said you know he
said almost nothing we do can't be
change next year and you know there's
just that he wasn't saying that the
debates weren't important he was saying
that we need to trust the process and
it's a Long View in how to do that and I
I think that's just right I you know the
idea that um you know and I I I also
think that it it's just a struggle right
now because we are becoming more
polarized there are things that are said
on the floor General Assembly that can
be very polarizing and um and so the
question is how do we deal with that you
know I read an article I think it was in
the Atlantic this week about you know
how so many people are throwing
temperature Tantrums in National Parks
right now and just there's just a lack
of Civility anytime you watch the news
or anything else and um unfortunately
there there's just a lot some of that is
leaking into the church as David strange
said a minute ago and um I do think the
question of what it means to be reminded
of not only the gospel and the
importance of both the mission of it and
the clarity of it or the the
foundational truth of it um but also in
how the Lord calls us to engage with one
another over these things and to
lovingly care and and actually to listen
to one another which is something that
we are just losing as a culture any
ability to actually listen to what the
other person is saying um and to be able
to engage uh well and argue well in the
midst of that and um you know I I I've
been in debates at General Assembly
where I felt like that has actually gone
well and and as a source of
encouragement like you know I I do think
the last two years in our over committee
it hasn't been quite as much on the
floor unfortunately but in the over
committee I felt like there's been
actually a lot of listening to one
another and a lot of uh helpful
engagement helpful dialogue around some
of these issues and so I'm not utterly
despairing over these things I know
people that are um but you know one of
the things that's interesting to me is
and I'd love to hear your guys' thought
on this is like you because I'm not sure
what to do about it is you know I I
heard somebody say one time like I wish
we could just cut the live feed and the
the reason for that is not because we
want to just hide everything from the
public right that's that's not is not
kind of trying to be secretive about it
but it is you're saying you're you're
not saying we should go into a conclave
no and you know but at the same time
like it you have to understand what
general assembly is and what it isn't
yeah right it you know we are coming
together as a court to argue about
particular issues and these are
important issues and as you're
discussing these things on the floor you
may get somebody stand up on the floor
and say something that that none of us
would agree with man well the vast
majority of the church would agree with
but that may be the you know the thing
that gets out and is kind of most
reported about and that's an important
thing to think about like I I do think
we have to trust the pro I think
bringing the level of Civility you know
back to a more Godly level of how we
engage and listen to one another but
also understanding and educating our
churches more about like what we're
doing and what it means when we had
these debates and that it you know
because there's a small minority of
people that are arguing on an extreme on
either side doesn't mean that that's
where the majority of the church
actually lands on this and I think it's
important to know that that in the
process of this or that this could take
years to get to a good point so yeah uh
it could David when when when you're
having conversations with pastors around
the country or or other Elders
um what where are the points of push
back on the
Overture um I've already written in
support of it but what are you have to
say RS and and see or big David and
Little David I'll let you choose who's
who yeah David strain David strain as
the as the U primary author mover uh
what what uh what are you hearing in
terms of push back on I don't know that
that's adequate I'm not sure this is
this is going to get the job done is
there any of that from from guys that
you're talking to what over in what
way I think some guys who are very
concerned
to be as tight and as precise as
possible
um who are you know who are very
conservative um and very
concerned even alarmed they they they
would read the Overture can I just read
the line that we inserted that help so
Overture 23 inserted a line into bco 82
and into 93 which is about
qualifications for Elder and
qualifications for
Deacon uh and it inserts into the those
paragraphs he should conform to the
biblical requirement of Chastity and
sexual Purity and his descriptions of
himself his convictions character and
conduct um and they would say the guys
that are pushing back against this from
a from a uh a position of alarm that the
church is becoming too broad too loose
on the question of sexuality they would
say this doesn't name specifically
homosexuality it doesn't go go after uh
the question of of identity those sorts
of things um guys on the other side of
that discussion who who think that we're
already plenty clear and
that um a lot of this is driven
by um
panic and that that Panic is
fundamentally a distraction from our
mission um really feel like this is
superfluous vocabul
that it's a waste of air time that it's
a distraction from our core work that it
all is doing is fueling the debate
rather than ending it those are the
sorts of those are the sorts of language
that I'm hearing from from both sides of
this but but my my read like the squeaky
wheel gets the grease right and and so
there's always going to be people who
are not pleased sure and and there's
really often a degree of validity on all
in many sides of these
concerns
but we were just talking off the air
about the way overtures happen and what
an overture really is the these things
as you pointed out earlier this is the
sausage making
business and that that is is messy yeah
it's you know an overture is there's a
certain level of pragmatic what can we
do not not what ought it to be in the
best of all possible
worlds um and and sometimes my brothers
who are well to my right or well to my
left on any given issue are
idealists I think I'm an idealist in a
good way you know I I cling to biblical
ideals I hope and I hope those
discipline my my pragmatism but there's
but discipline pragmatism m is good
and uh trying to find consensus around
shared convictions is the right approach
and that's that's what we're trying to
do in this Overture it seems to me that
the study the ad interim study committee
report on human
sexuality really helpfully clarified an
awful lot gave good
categories settled some discussions
helped form um the way that we speak
about this issue in very biblical very
faithful and very pastoral ways the the
the committee served the denomination
really well and while there is still
debate and disagreement in some segments
of the church on both extremes about
this the majority of our denomination
stands right there and has clarity about
that I think um the question has been do
we need to put things in in our book
that reflects that
Clarity and my hope is that together
with the two overtures that we passed
from the previous assembly this will get
us there in a way that allows us to move
on to other issues and to your point
earlier I know I'm talking too much so
forgive me um three preachers in the
room beautiful
SC um uh to to the point about slowness
there is a bless
sacred sless especially to
presbyterianism it is a deliberative
thing it takes our church years even
when we are agreed in one assembly you
know it still takes us till the
following year to finally ratify a
decision and more often than not that
Overture that goes through that process
and
meets the standard of Presby approval
and then gets ratified by the following
assembly has had previous iterations in
a couple of assemblies before that that
got shot
down um and the the framers of those
overtures have typically listened to the
reasoning and gone back and tried to
take that push back on board and to find
a way that allows them still to hit the
target they were originally aiming at
but acknowledges the valid criticisms
and concerns that they've heard and I
think I think that while along the way
sometimes things get said and people's
temper gets freed and all of that you
put 2,000 people in a room and ask them
to debate that's going to happen on
almost any given issue it just is yeah
but but that
accepted that process to me is really a
beautiful thing and I I am really I'm
actually really optimistic about the
PCA um because on the one hand I've seen
US Express remarkable clarity about our
core
convictions and and I do not see the
evidence of the alleged precipitous
decline into liberalism that I'm hearing
from
some and at the same time I'm also
seeing churches get
planted and Ministry get done and people
being bold and sacrificial and
courageous to preach Christ all across
our nation and all around the world and
I I don't see the
PCA losing momentum in trying to fulfill
its
Mission I think it's easy to think that
we are because we come we may come out
of an assembly a particular assembly
limping a little and frustrated over any
particular matter that we wished went
differently but I think as as David RoR
said a minute ago Let's Take the Long
View and looked at over you know 10
years 20 years over our 50 years I think
we see the hand of God at work and we
see him continuing to work for the
health uh and the the blessing of our
people and for the glory of his name in
ways that I think are frankly thrilling
I I'm not at all pessimistic about our
denom denominational
Direction it's it's worth pointing out I
think too that like anybody who
remembers when we used to do overtures
on the floor of the assembly in front of
everybody oh man we used to do the same
you know judicial stuff on the floor I
mean it was a nightmare it was an
absolute nightmare I do think that the
process is actually working better now
and we're more deliberative now because
our overtures committee is fully
representative of our presbyteries yeah
teach and there's parity between
teaching and ruling Elders there are
different rules in our debate so that's
it's just a manageable Frank full real
deliberative debate and overtures that
as you say David has gone actually very
well there's a lot of hard work done
listening trying to understand finding
consensus amendments that can pass that
work has been wonderful and very
encouraging to
see one of the I I completely share your
optimism by the way David uh about the
next 50 years you know how much it costs
me to be this optimistic as a Scots I I
know that's painful very difficult I
know
um and one of the reasons I I I want to
say that is because of what you just
said what which I think is incredibly
important that you
don't uh you know buy into the kind
of you know much vaunted and much
advertised line that the PCA is drifting
into some kind of theological liberalism
I just don't see that happening right um
it's theologically conservative and
biblically conservative I think there
are um uh fears that are
unfounded in in that um uh approach that
says that we're we're headed that headed
that direction I just don't think it's
true and that isn't to say that there
isn't someone somewhere or some church
somewhere that uh wouldn't be um moving
that direction um but the truth is as a
whole as a denomination that's just not
where we're at and by the way that Unity
that we expressed in the
uh vote on the reception of the addin
term committee's
report demonstrates that actually not
just Unity but conservative approach to
the issue um I was very very grateful
for that and it's the basis of uh some
work we're doing pastorally with our
congregation uh starting in September
later this month uh over a seven-week
series on Wednesday nights we're really
using that as the base basis of some
teaching that we're doing and I know
many churches are doing that so I'm very
very grateful for those efforts and I
think it highlights when we do get
together on these things and work
through stuff we're not going to make
everybody happy that's to be sure but we
will arrive at places of of uh I think
better understanding greater
Clarity um yeah I I think when we do
disagree actually we help each other
learn so I'm not opposed to any of the
disagreements per se Spirit of some of
them unpleasant but I think the
disagreements actually help us grow in
our understanding grow in our wisdom I'm
grateful for that and I'm grateful for
the glacial pace of some of it I also
understand and I think you referred to
this why it's necessary for us
to um see this Overture as an
opportunity to put some of that now to
rest and why do you think that's
possible
or important
now if if we if if this goes through
presbyteries pass it we get the the
two-thirds and it comes back to the
assembly go okay there's that um is
there do do you have good reason for
thinking okay I think I think this does
it at least for this season on this
issue my my sense of the PCA right now
is this one
issue has has been aired so thly that a
lot of a lot of people across the
board are are ready to move on yeah and
uh feel like we've addressed the
matter and uh we you know we've we've
come to I mean even the vote on 23 at
this past assembly was so overwhelming
both on the floor that sort of signals
to me that mood that that okay we can
get together on this and we're we're
ready as a church to after having
expressed our mind in multiple different
ways the Nashville statement the ad
interim committee report previous
overtures that are now in our book this
Overture uh debates that have been had
seminars at General Assembly you know
not to mention all the many many um
discussions in churches on podcasts and
blogs and and all the other places we've
we've been talking about almost nothing
else for how long has it been five years
is it more than at least at least a long
time uh I would say eight years eight
eight to nine years yeah a long time
and um you know some people are leaving
the PCA because they're not
satisfied uh others actually on both
extremes right right they want the PCA
to be much much narrower or or are much
less vocal on the issue and don't either
don't feel
safe or don't feel
aligned um theologically any longer um
but but those are not vast numbers the
the bulk of our
denomination I think is is clear on the
matter and ready to move on that's not
to say that there won't be other debates
there inevit well of course and many of
those will be necessary and good sure or
there won't be overes
because literally every individual
person could take could write it over
yeah sure but my instinct if I was a
betting man it would be that another
over
tour really won't have a lot of legs at
a following General Assembly if it's on
this specific issue yeah it's just
that's my that's my sense of the mood I
I may be totally wrong about that but
that's my sense yeah and it's and it's
worth saying that just because there's
an overture on something does not mean
that that the denomination has any
appetite for actually dealing with that
or that that's not representative I mean
we get overtures all the time that can
be pretty far out there right on
different things and so you know if we
get an overture this next year on
something like this that doesn't we need
to wait and see how the denomination
responds it doesn't mean that that we're
going to continue this on I think that's
worth saying right I'd love to ask one
question as we're kind of concluding
like what do you guys think that we can
learn from the past eight years of our
debates on this to be more Godly to be
more faithful to you know to approach
this in a better way going
forward that's such a great question
David
question
um I think the first thing I would note
is a
patient
listening the
the the real posture of heart that says
I'm trying to hear what your concern is
rather than simply arguing for my
position um as convinced as I may be
about my
position I want to be able to deeply
hear
not just the position of the other
person but the concern of the other
person uh to enter into that in some way
to try
to um grasp what's moving
that uh I think that would that's one of
the most important things we we have to
do um that doesn't mean that I I I have
to affirm that concern I may come to the
conclusion that I think that concern is
invalid it's misplaced it's
overwrought uh it's
overemphasized in but I still need to
understand it and uh I think sometimes
we are I mean for myself uh um too quick
to come to the defense of my
position um and the implications of what
I believe would go against it rather
than really listening
to what someone else is concerned
about yeah I I don't think I can
I agree with every word you just said
there David I you know slow to
speak quick to
listen um I think we all
could we all can acknowledge that we've
not always done that well we need to
seek each other's
forgiveness and pardon we need to pursue
each other I I think I think
[Music]
the idea that we have enemies in our
denomination is really disturbing to me
and there are people who who speak that
way they definitely do I I do not have
any enemies right to my knowledge I'm
not I'm people may view me that way I
don't I don't have any enemies I have
opponents on all kinds of issues you
know who on the other side of an issue
and we're going to we're going to debate
and we're going to Wrangle we're going
to get frustrated even and we're going
to differ but they are my brothers in
Christ
I they are not my
enemy and that that needs to constantly
discipline my attitude in the way that I
carry myself in the speech that I use in
the words that I say in my head that
don't even come out of my mouth what I
say in here about you yeah matters as
much as what I say out of my mouth
toward you or in the presence of others
about you and uh I mean that that what
we're talking about now is
sanctification it's it's it's it's being
humble it's it's it's trying to uh be
patient with one another because we're
we belong to the same Savior and ult
ultimately we are
dishonoring the
cross the work of
Christ when when
we uh think the worst of one another and
leap to conclusions yeah I'm not
advocating for peace peace when there is
no
peace and I don't think you are either I
I think I think either of us are in any
danger
right we need to be able and we need
each other to to challenge and and help
us see what we're missing and and you
know call we need to be calling each
other out and that that's Godly and
right yes there are de debates that have
to be had that are important for the
health of the church and the furtherance
of the
Gospel
but how we have
them uh really really matters it really
really
matters uh so I'm that's part I'm very
grateful for you both and for the
opportunity
to to to have these sorts of
conversations together to do them
publicly um to try and imperfectly model
some of that
oh it's a joy David thank you for taking
the time on that and sharing so
much this has been great thank you guys
so much it's been wonderful to be with
you and have a little conversation about
this